Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajpurohit and today I am presenting to you
a new product launched by HDFC Life Insurance whose name is Sampoorna Jeevan.
Here you
can get income from the first month and life time income till 100 years. Here you are given many options of policy. You
can run the policy till your age of 75 years. You can also run the policy for life time. If you want a
short term policy, you want a policy for 25 years, 30 years, 35 years, 40 years, then also you
can select. You may have to pay premium for 6 years, 8 years, 10 years, 12 years,
15 years. There are many options. You
can pay premium for 6 years or 15 years and also run the policy for 100 years. Here you will also get cash bonus, guaranteed benefits and
income tax benefits. So watch this video of mine completely.
I have explained all the options in detail to you. If you like the video, then like, share and subscribe to my YouTube channel Anil Rajpurohit FFFS.
Now watch There are four guaranteed options in this plan, let me explain it to you in full details. There
are five bonus options in ADFC Sampoorna Jeevan and five bonus options in HPFC Sampoorna Jeevan,
so there will be a total of nine options, so it will be quite confusing, but you
should watch the video completely, I will explain it to you in detail and you will definitely understand it.
If you watch this video
quickly, I will try to explain it to you in detail
with illustrations. The first benefit is that there
will be insurance cover in it. One option is up to 75 years, one is up to 100 years.
You can select any one of these or
you can also select premium payment time of 25, 30, 35, 40 paise. In policy term and premium payment time,
you will get the option of 6 years, 8 years, 10 years, 12 years and 15 years
. You will get different options in different options. Now
, beyond the main thing that you get, I will try to explain to you, you
will get money in two ways, one is guaranteed. You will get money under the benefit in which you
are given four options - Lum Sum Income Option, Lum Sum with Income Option and Income with Lum Sum Option. These
are the four options. All these options will be guaranteed. So firstly, you
will get income in this way. Secondly, the income that you will get will come under bonus. Five options of bonus have been given.
One is Simple Revisionary Bonus.
One is Simple Revisionary Income Bonus. One is Cash Bonus. One is Simple Revisionary Bonus. Premium Payment Term and
Cash Bonus is after that and the fifth is Simple Revisionary Income Bonus and
Cash Bonus. I will try to explain all these five to you in a little simple language.
First of all, you understand the payout option. I will
explain to you the guaranteed portion again. If you have selected the Lum Sum Option Guaranteed in the payout option, then you
will get 100% of the basic income on maturity. Secondly, if you
have selected the Income Option, on completion of premium payment, you will start receiving
annual income. What will happen in the off 5 per off basic semester income option is that you will get
premium payment of 5 per cent of your basic semester every year after the completion of the term.
The third is Lump Sum with Income option. Here it means that when the customer
turns 60 years old, he will get 100% of the basic sum and after that if
he has taken the option of 100 years, then he will get the basic sum at 5 per cent and
if he has taken the option of last year, then he will get that basic sum at 10 per cent every year and the fourth is Income
with Lump Sum option. Here, at the age of 61, whichever you select,
you will get the basic sum at 5 per cent and at 10 per cent and finally you will get 100% of the basic sum. So these
are the four options. When I explain in the illustration, you will have to keep in mind
which option you have taken. When will you get the money? Will you get the money all at once? Will you
get the entire money at the age of 60? Then income will come every year? Will income come every year? Then
You will get the full amount in the 7th year or you will get the full amount at 75, so these three or four options are given,
which one is guaranteed, now how will the
bonus option work for you, if you have taken Simple Revisionary Bonus for Term,
it means you will get it either at death or at maturity, whichever
is earlier, you will get this Simple Revisionary Bonus on that, okay, for example, you
had taken a policy term of 75 years, if you survived for 75 years, then whatever your Simple
Revisionary Bonus accumulated, you will get it on maturity, okay, now if
you have taken Simple Revisionary Income Bonus option, it means that
the bonus will be declared from the first year itself, but when will you start getting it, premium payment term
After completion, suppose if the company has given you any bonus, then when will you get it?
After 15 years, that is, at 16 years, declared in the second year and at 17 years, what
was declared in the third year, you will get it at the age of 18. When will the company declare it in your policy,
but when will you get it after the completion of the premium payment term?
Now, if you have taken a cash bonus, then cash bonus means that it will immediately
come to your account in the year in which you declare it. The fourth option
is Simple Revisionary Bonus for premium payment and cash bonus after that. So here
it means Simple Revisionary Bonus is declared and accrued annually during the
premium payment and payable at the end of premium payment term. This means that
the premium payment term will be completed at that time when all your revisionary bonuses will be added and
given together. Suppose your premium payment term is 15 years.
Whatever amount of Simple Revisionary Bonus is accumulated for 15 years, suppose if 15 lakhs is accumulated then 15 lakhs. You will get it all at once,
after that you will get a cash bonus every year. A cash income
will also start coming into your account every year. The fifth one is Simple Revisionary Income Bonus. It is both SRIB and Cash
Bonus. What does this mean? This combination
is a combination of Option 2 and Option 3. What is Option 2? Simple Revisionary Income Bonus, that is, if
it is declared in the first year, it will be received at the age of 16. If it is declared in the second year, it will be received at the age of 17.
Premium payment in this way. And the cash bonus which is received every year,
you can select any of these 500 options. So, there is an income option for you that you
will get money under bonus. You will get guaranteed money in these 500 options. So,
this is the entire plan, it is a bit confusing, but when you see the example,
everything will become clear to you. I will explain the illustration in two minutes. Till then,
I will tell you a little about the rest of the policy term, premium payment terms, etc., what all are there,
what benefits you will get in this policy and in what manner
. Now you should see that first of all you should see what is
the option of premium payment term, if you have taken the policy for whole life till the age of 75, then
what will be the minimum age of entry, that if your premium payment term is
12, 6 years, 8 years, 10 years, 12 years or 15 years, if the premium
payment term is this, then if the premium payment term is 6 years, then the minimum entry term
is 12 years, 8 years, if the premium payment term is 10 years, then
the minimum entry term is 8 years, 12 years, if the premium payment term is 12 years, then even a person of 6 years
can take this policy, if the premium payment term is 15 years, then you can purchase the policy for a 3 year old child also,
if you are taking whole life for 100 years, then the minimum
age of the person should be 18 years, now these four options which are given to you, guaranteed benefit
option to 4, which I have told you all four, in that option of lump sum income, you
can see that You can easily see how much minimum entry fee should be there in which premium payment term,
how much maximum entry fee should be there. Talking about the policy term
, you can take the full 75 years or you can select 25, 30, 35, 40, whichever
you want to select. Talking about death benefit, the sum is the insurance cover
plus the bonus you have selected as option, cash bonus plus if any paid addition has been taken
and terminal bonus if declared by the company, then by combining these five you
get the death benefit. If death occurs then you will get that, if death does not occur then you
will get maturity benefit. You can see here how you will get the maturity benefit,
basic sum plus whichever bonus you select out of the five plus terminal
bonus if declared by the company, then in these four options you can see
on which bonuses you will get the maturity benefit. Talking about survival benefit,
I have told you 500 options, out of which you will get guaranteed from when When income
starts coming, then this is survival benefit, if death happens,
how much money will be received on death, how much money will be received on maturity and how much money will you
get every year, he gets survival benefit, now I
will explain it to you one by one illustration, now you keep looking here again and again,
here you are given many options, there is an immediate income solution,
you will get regular income plus lump sum maturity will be given only once, here there
is regular income, you will get maturity twice, you will also get regular income thrice
maturity, a policy holder can decide himself that he
wants maturity along with income, you will get an option to deposit under paid addition and then
I also want to withdraw a part from it like ULIP, suppose you have invested Rs. 50 lakh
The bonus has been deposited and you can withdraw it if needed. If you want more income,
you can also take it. So, I will try to explain all these options to you. First of all,
I
will explain the immediate income option. There is a person whose name is Anil Rajpat, his age
is 35 years. I have kept the age of 35 years in all the illustrations, here I have kept the premium
payment term as 15 years only and I have kept the premium amount as ₹ lakh,
this is common in all and I have taken the 100 year option, this means that you
are seeing the policy term as 65 years. The name of the plan is ADFC Life Sampoorna Jeevan and
if you see here, in Sampoorna Jeevan, I have taken the 100 year option, I
have selected the Lussum option, Lussum Income and there were four options, out of which I selected the Lussum option.
In bonus, I have selected the cash bonus option from five options. Here,
how much BSA 9365 from the basic time, if you want to understand all these calculations,
then now you
can see the customer's points. From the point of view, you have paid Rs 1 lakh each for 15 years,
you should come to column number eight because you are taking cash bonus, so in the first year itself
you are getting a cash bonus of Rs 44375, that is, you should look in column number 13 and get Rs 44375, that is,
you should look at the total survivor benefit in column number 17, one is 4 + 7 + 12 + 13,
by adding the total amount in the fourth column, seventh column, 12 column and 13 column,
you will see here that Rs 44000 is coming to you every year, the customer paid the premium in 2023,
from 2024 itself, that is, on 16 October 2024, he
will get Rs 34375, in this way, money will start coming to him every year, here when he
turns 65, you will see Rs 55464 instead of 44, if you
are watching on mobile then make it full screen, tilt the phone, make it horizontal and
watch high quality video So, if you are looking at it on u, then in this way you
are getting an income of Rs 55000 every year, then you will get an income of Rs 66000 and finally you
will also get a maturity of Rs 2 crore 57 26165, which option did you select, the immediate
one, now I will tell you the second option, which is the regular income with one
lump sum payout
, the same 35 year old person will pay premium for 15 years, the premium is of one lakh rupees,
here I have selected income option instead of lump sum, you
will see cash bonus here, you should also see this option, what is there in
income option and I had told you how the cash bonus income option works,
you had seen here income option, income option means that
after completion of premium payment term, you will get 5% guaranteed every year, so now you will see here
that when your premium payment term is completed in 15 years, then 5% of whose
basic sum, basic sum assures your How much basic sum assured in the policy
is 906253, so 5% of 906253 is
45313 on which guarantee will also be written, so you have got the first option and
you are getting cash bonus every year, how much bonus are you getting, that is
36250, now you see, in the beginning you are getting cash bonus of 36000 and
when the premium payment term is complete for 15 years, then you are getting 5% guaranteed, so 36 and
45 become 81000, now you are getting income of 81000, then you are getting income of 90000 and
then you are getting maturity of 2 crore 38 lakh on the policy, now we
see the next option and the name of that option is
Regular Income One with Two Lump Sum Benefit Pay
Out Two, it means that here now you will get maturity twice, the same
is a 35 year old person, premium paid for 15 years, policy lasts for 65 years The premium is of one lakh rupees.
Now, which option have you taken here? You have selected the Lump Sum with Income option and
which is the bonus option? Simple Revisionary Income Bonus plus Cash Bonus. Now let me
explain this once again. Look
at the Lump Sum with Income option. You are seeing the Lump Sum with Income option here.
What does it mean that when you turn 60, you
will get 100% basic sum assured and after that, you will get 5% of the basic sum assured.
So, look here,
if you are 35 years old, then after 25 years, you will turn 60, then you
will get 931612 basic sum. You have got your full basic sum of 931612,
after that you will also get 5% of it, i.e., 46581. The first portion is
guaranteed. Which is the second portion with bonus? Simple Revisionary Income Bonus and Cash
Bonus. Let me explain this also to you, how the bonus is working.
Which option in bonus should you select? There is Simple Revisionary Bonus and Cash Bonus i.e. Option
Two and Option Three. Here you can see when you get Simple Revisionary Bonus and
when you get Income Bonus. After completion of premium payment, you get the entire amount together.
Here, whatever your Simple Revisionary Income Bonus is deposited till the premium payment,
you will get it all at once and after that you have cash bonus which will come every year, so now you
see in this option that here your Simple Revisionary Bonus of 37264
is being declared every year, keep adding 37 37, then here you will see that as soon as
your premium payment time is completed, firstly you are getting this total money here and this is your
Simple Revisionary Bonus, let me try to explain all three to you,
like how is the income of 102477 coming here, firstly
you are getting 46000 guaranteed, secondly the 18000 cash bonus which is coming and thirdly
your Revisionary Bonus of 37000 is being declared every year, if you add these three
then you will get 102477, so it will keep coming to you in this way, you will
get maturity of 2 crore 16 lakh, now let us understand one more option,
the name of that option
is thrice You can take lump sum and there will be benefit of regular income as well, so now you
see here
, first time there is a maturity of 631000, second maturity of 1094000 and
third maturity of 1 crore 70 lakh and you are getting income every year, so in this way
you can also select how all these calculations
came, lump sum with income option is taken, simple revisionary bonus during premium
payment and cash bonus there after, so in this way I have explained the complete calculation to you
that at the age of 60 you get full BSA, then you
get 5% of the basic sum assured guaranteed, the bonus that you have accumulated for 15 years is how much, total 631000,
you got 631000 here and here you got the full basic sum assured at the age of 60,
so these are the two maturities and cash bonus and by adding all this you
are getting income every year and the final one Maturity is coming, so now you need one maturity at the end,
you need one maturity in the middle, you need two maturities, you need income every year, you
can select this as per your need, now let us see the next option is
Regular Income with Policy Older to decide additional lump sum pay during the policy
term, the customer is 35 years, the premium to be paid is 15 years, here he has
taken the income option, cash bonus is given but here he has taken paid up addition, that is, if he
wants to deposit, he can do it, so now you will see here that every
year income of 47000 is coming, 45000 and the first maturity has come, see here
5462000 is coming, when is it coming at the age of 74, and then you
will also get a maturity of 2 crore 38 lakh rupees, so if you want to select the option in this way also,
then you can do it, there is another option which
will be called Endowment with Option Parcel Withdrawal, now in this option also I have added lump sum
Sum and cash bonus etc. are given and now you
see that you are getting 70 lakhs out of 75 together, then income is coming, then maturity is
coming of 2 crore 57 lakhs and the final option that you will get to see will be
Enhance Income with Lump Sum at Maturity,
here you see sum means if you want more income then the income will be shown in increasing order,
here you are getting income of 139396 every year and it
is increasing till 158000 and then you are getting 2 crore 17 lakhs on maturity,
you will also get the column of death benefit every time at the last 18th or 19th number in every option,
so now you can decide yourself which type of option you want to take that from the first
year itself I get 44000 against lakhs and then in the end the policy should mature at the age of 100,
the second option is that you get cash bonus from the first year, then you will get
guaranteed income 36000 increases to 81000, then to 90000, then only one
maturity comes, the third option you are getting is that brother I am
getting 18000 income in the first year but then I am getting 55000, in between I am getting maturity of
around 987000 at the age of 60, then income of lakh rupees is coming every year and then
maturity of 2 crore is also coming, then you tell the option that I
do not want income immediately, after a few years maturity comes twice, so here once
631000 is coming, once 1094000 is coming, 420000 and you are getting income of ₹ 1 lakh every year,
115000 is also coming, then maturity of 1cr 70 lakh is also coming, then if you
want the option that I do not want income immediately, then later you can invest 45000 rupees every year You are taking income every year
, then you are taking Rs. 54 lakhs separately, at the age of 75, even after that
you are getting an income of Rs. 90000, you are getting maturity of Rs. 2 crore 38 lakhs, suppose
you die even after taking this, then also see your death benefit of Rs. 5574000
will remain even after this or if there is death here, then 80 lakhs will be given to the family members, this one
You took the income, this income was coming to your account every year and finally you
can see that if you want to get Rs 70 lakh here all at once and then every year income
comes and a match, now according to your need you can decide which option you want
to select, you can take this policy in that option,
so finally if I review this policy, then from the customer point of view, this
is a policy with very good features, your needs have been completely taken into consideration, whether
you want early income, you want late income, you want one maturity, you want two maturities, which
bonus option you want to select, which income option you want to select, then you
can select anything as per your need, here you will
also get tax benefit under section ATC of income tax, whatever benefit you are getting, whatever income you are getting,
whatever maturity you are getting, all of it will be tax free under section 10 10D of income tax,
here you will also get loan facility,
if you want to take a loan, then you You can also take a loan. Under the riders, there
is a critical illness rider and an income rider. You can also add those riders
in this policy. So if you like the video, then definitely like, share and subscribe to my YouTube channel Anil Rajpurohit FFFS.
If you want, my mobile number
is 9909403412. Jai
Hind.